<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<!-- This is a WordPress eXtended RSS file generated by WordPress as an export of your site. -->
<!-- It contains information about your site's posts, pages, comments, categories, and other content. -->
<!-- You may use this file to transfer that content from one site to another. -->
<!-- This file is not intended to serve as a complete backup of your site. -->

<!-- To import this information into a WordPress site follow these steps: -->
<!-- 1. Log in to that site as an administrator. -->
<!-- 2. Go to Tools: Import in the WordPress admin panel. -->
<!-- 3. Install the "WordPress" importer from the list. -->
<!-- 4. Activate & Run Importer. -->
<!-- 5. Upload this file using the form provided on that page. -->
<!-- 6. You will first be asked to map the authors in this export file to users -->
<!--    on the site. For each author, you may choose to map to an -->
<!--    existing user on the site or to create a new user. -->
<!-- 7. WordPress will then import each of the posts, pages, comments, categories, etc. -->
<!--    contained in this file into your site. -->

<!-- generator="WordPress/3.4.2" created="2014-02-07 08:59" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:excerpt="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/excerpt/"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:wp="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/"
>

<channel>
	<title>MetabolicMine</title>
	<link>http://blog.metabolicmine.org</link>
	<description>data mining common metabolic diseases</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2014 08:59:08 +0000</pubDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<wp:wxr_version>1.2</wp:wxr_version>
	<wp:base_site_url>http://blog.metabolicmine.org</wp:base_site_url>
	<wp:base_blog_url>http://blog.metabolicmine.org</wp:base_blog_url>

	<wp:author><wp:author_id>1</wp:author_id><wp:author_login>admin</wp:author_login><wp:author_email>hostmaster@flymine.org</wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[admin]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>
	<wp:author><wp:author_id>2</wp:author_id><wp:author_login>Richard</wp:author_login><wp:author_email>richard@flymine.org</wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[Richard]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[Richard]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[Smith]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>

	<wp:category><wp:term_id>3</wp:term_id><wp:category_nicename>events</wp:category_nicename><wp:category_parent></wp:category_parent><wp:cat_name><![CDATA[events]]></wp:cat_name></wp:category>
	<wp:category><wp:term_id>4</wp:term_id><wp:category_nicename>new-release</wp:category_nicename><wp:category_parent></wp:category_parent><wp:cat_name><![CDATA[New Release]]></wp:cat_name></wp:category>
	<wp:category><wp:term_id>1</wp:term_id><wp:category_nicename>uncategorized</wp:category_nicename><wp:category_parent></wp:category_parent><wp:cat_name><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></wp:cat_name></wp:category>
	<wp:tag><wp:term_id>3</wp:term_id><wp:tag_slug>events</wp:tag_slug><wp:tag_name><![CDATA[events]]></wp:tag_name></wp:tag>
	<wp:tag><wp:term_id>4</wp:term_id><wp:tag_slug>new-release</wp:tag_slug><wp:tag_name><![CDATA[New Release]]></wp:tag_name></wp:tag>

	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.4.2</generator>

	<item>
		<title>About</title>
		<link>http://blog.metabolicmine.org/about/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2010 12:43:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.metabolicmine.org/?page_id=2</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[metabolicMine is a data warehouse that integrates diverse biological data sets and  the tools to explore them. The main focus of metabolicMine is genomics and proteomics of  common metabolic diseases. By integrating such data into one place it is possible to  construct queries across domains of biological knowledge.

To get started, why not take the <strong>Tour</strong> or look through the <strong>Feature Hints</strong> from the Home Page (located in the 'First Time Here?' box). In order to access the full range of database features, please set up a MyMine account (click the MyMine tab located on the top menu bar on any metabolicMine page).

Please Note: This is our latest 'beta' preview of metabolicMine.

metabolicMine is under continued development by a team of software developers and biologists in the <a href="http://www.sysbiol.cam.ac.uk/" target="_new">Cambridge Systems Biology Centre</a> at Cambridge University. Please help us to improve the site by sending us your comments, questions and bugs: <a href="mailto:metabolicmine@intermine.org">metabolicmine [at] intermine.org</a>
<h3>The metabolicMine Team</h3>
Current members:
<table style="height: 136px;" border="0" width="368">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Gos Micklem</td>
<td>Project Leader</td>
<td><a href="mailto:gos@flymine.org">gos [at] flymine.org</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Richard Smith</td>
<td>Software Team Leader</td>
<td><a href="mailto:richard@flymine.org">richard [at] flymine.org</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Adrian Carr</td>
<td>Senior Biologist</td>
<td><a href="mailto:adrian@flymine.org">adrian [at] flymine.org</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Mike Lyne</td>
<td>Senior Biologist</td>
<td><a href="mailto:mike@intermine.org">mike [at] intermine.org</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Rachel Lyne</td>
<td>Senior Biologist</td>
<td><a href="mailto:rachel@flymine.org">rachel [at] flymine.org</a></td>
</tr>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Radek Stepan</td>
<td>Web Developer</td>
<td><a href="mailto:radek@intermine.org">radek [at] intermine.org</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Dan Tomlinson</td>
<td>Systems Administrator</td>
<td><a href="mailto:dan@intermine.org">dan [at] intermine.org</a></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
Alumni:
<table style="height: 136px;" border="0" width="368">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td colspan="2">Matthew Wakeling</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td colspan="2">Nils Koelling (intern)</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h3>Funding</h3>
metabolicMine is funded by a Wellcome Trust Technology Development Grant (ref # 090297/Z09/Z).
<h3>Collaborators</h3>
<table style="height: 136px;" border="0" width="368">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Dr. Inês Barosso</td>
<td>WT Sanger Institute, Hinxton</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Dr. Ewan Birney</td>
<td>European Bioinformatics Institute, Hinxton</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Prof. Roger Cox</td>
<td>MRC Harwell</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Prof. Tim Frayling</td>
<td>PMS, Exeter</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Prof. Philippe Froguel</td>
<td>Imperial College, London</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Dr. Suzanna Lewis</td>
<td>Life Sciences, Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Dr. Ruth Loos</td>
<td>MRC Epidemiology Unit, Cambridge</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Prof. Mark McCarthy</td>
<td>WTCHG, Oxford</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Prof. Steve O'Rahilly</td>
<td>IMS, Cambridge</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Prof. Antonio Vidal-Puig</td>
<td>IMS, Cambridge</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h3>Help Us</h3>
metabolicMine needs your help! Please send us (<a href="mailto:metabolicmine@intermine.org">metabolicmine [at] intermine.org</a>) your suggestions on:
<ul>
	<li>How you'd like to use the site</li>
	<li>How we can improve the site</li>
	<li>What new features and data to include</li>
</ul>

<h3>Logo</h3>
<img src="http://blog.metabolicmine.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/metabolicMine_logo.png" alt="mm logo" title="metabolicMine_logo" width="45" height="43" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-42" style="float: left; padding-right: 10px; background-color: #FFFBD8;"/>The metabolicMine logo was designed by Lily Oaks - <a href="http://www.lillyoaks.com">http://www.lillyoaks.com</a> as part of the <a href="http://gmod.org/wiki/GMOD_Logo_Program">GMOD logo program</a> with the <a href="http://www.linnbenton.edu/">Linn-Benton Community College</a>.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>2</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2010-08-13 12:43:56</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2010-08-13 12:43:56</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>about</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>page</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_page_template</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>FAQ</title>
		<link>http://blog.metabolicmine.org/faq/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2010 10:42:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.metabolicmine.org/?page_id=7</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>I. General FAQ about metabolicMine</h1>
<h2>Q. How can I query metabolicMine?</h2>
metabolicMine provides three web-based ways to query the integrated data: A QuickSearch, predefined Template queries and a QueryBuilder. The metabolicMine tour (accessible from the homepage) shows a very brief overview of how to use metabolicMine.
<ol>
	<li> QuickSearch: Allows you to browse the database, starting from a particular name or identifier. This is very useful if you do not have a particular query you want to run and want to browse all the information or specific information about a particular entry in the database. A QuickSearch box is available on the metabolicMine homepage (orange Search box) and in the top menu bar on every metabolicMine page.</li>
	<li>Template queries: These predefined queries provide quick and easy access to the data. A Template query basically consists of a form, in which you fill in the boxes to define your query. Template queries range from fairly simple queries to complex queries covering two or more datasets. Templates can be accessed from the purple box on the front page or from the Templates tab on the top menu bar on every page.</li>
	<li>The QueryBuilder: Advanced users can use a flexible query interface to construct their own data mining queries across the multiple integrated data sources, to modify existing Template queries or to create their own Template queries. Access the metabolicMine QueryBuilder via the QueryBuilder tab in the top menu bar on every metabolicMine page.</li>
</ol>
<h2>Q. Can I do a search for a set of Genes all at once, instead of one at the time?</h2>
It depends on the type of search you want to do. The QuickSearch box does not accept more than one entry yet, but the Template queries and the QueryBuilder do. To do so, you need to create a List of all the Genes you're interested in and constrain your search to the Genes in your List.
<h2>Q. How can I create a metabolicMine account?</h2>
Click on the 'Log in' link on the top right of every metabolicMine page or on the MyMine page. If you have never logged in before, go to '..or create an account'. Enter your email address, choose a password and confirm it and click on 'Create account'. You can then log in. Your username is the email address for which you chose a password. If you forgot your password, click on 'forgotten password'. You will be asked to enter your email address. Click on 'Request password' and your password will then be sent to you again.
<h2>Q. How do I cite metabolicMine?</h2>
<a title="Cite metabolicMine" href="http://blog.metabolicmine.org/cite">Click here for further information</a>.
<h2>Q. Help! My question hasn't been answered!</h2>
Please contact us! Email us at support[at]intermine.org with any questions you may have. We're always glad to hear from InterMine users!
<h1>II. Data</h1>
<h2>Q. How can I find out what data are in metabolicMine?</h2>
The data in metabolicMine are divided into categories for easy navigation. Clicking on a data Tab (in the top menu bar) at the top of any page will display a page that provides:
<ol>
	<li> More detailed information about the actual data loaded.</li>
	<li>Access to bulk download for this data.</li>
	<li>A set of Template queries related to this type of query (some spanning data from other data categories).</li>
	<li>A set of starting points for using the QueryBuilder.</li>
</ol>
For a summary table of all data available in metabolicMine, click on the data tab in the top menu bar on any metabolicMine page.
<h2>Q. How can I find out where the results of my query originally come from?</h2>
If you have run a Template query, there will be one or more columns in the results table which will show the original dataset or the publication that the result originated from.
If you are building your own query using the QueryBuilder, to find the dataset you need to constrain the evidence class to 'Dataset' and choose fields from this class to show in your results. For many types of data there will also be a 'publication' class available. This is often more useful than the dataset class as the dataset class shows where we got the information from (eg Intact for protein interaction data) rather than the original publication of the data.
We are currently working on trying to make it more clear what the orginal dataset is (including which version).
<h1>III. Report Pages</h1>
<h2>Q. How can I find a report page?</h2>
Report pages can be accessed using the QuickSearch box on the metabolicMine homepage or on the top menu bar of every metabolicMine page, or from result tables or Lists by clicking on an object that provides a link. If you are using the QuickSearch box, you may be taken to a report page directly if only one object in the database matches your search.
<h1>IV. Lists</h1>
<h2>(For illustrated examples, see the Lists sections of the Tour - accessible from the home page)</h2>
<h2>Q. What is a List?</h2>
A List is any set of objects of the same type (eg. a List of Genes, a List of SNPs or a List of proteins).
<h2>Q. What is a Public List?</h2>
Public Lists are Lists that we have made for you. They are mostly sets of interesting Genes from publications. Public Lists can be identified as they always begin PL xxxx.

If you have suggestions for a must-have Gene set that we could include as a Public List, please do let us know (support[at]intermine.org).
<h2>Q. What can I do with Lists?</h2>
Lists can be used in three different ways: to refine a search (aka, constraining a query; either a Template query or a query constructed using the QueryBuilder), to save search results within metabolicMine and to perform logical operations (that is, combine or add data from different Lists).
Any Template search (aka Template query) can be 'constrained' to search using a List (or 'not in' a List) rather than to a single value. That is, provided you have a List of the correct type saved in MyMine (or a Public List). For example, if you want to run a particular Template search for a List of Genes rather than a single Gene, you can create a List of Genes and run a Template query on the members this List. To constrain a search to a List, select the checkbox underneath the variable box and choose the List from the drop-down List.
<ol>
	<li>Lists of data can be used to constrain queries in the QueryBuilder. If you have Lists of saved data under MyMine you will automatically be able to use these from within the QueryBuilder to constrain a query. When a field is selected for constraining a query using the QueryBuilder the constraint options in the right hand constraint panel will ask you to either 'Filter query results on this field having a specific value' or 'Filter query results on the contents of your List'. This latter option will only appear if you have Lists of the correct type saved in MyMine. To add a List constraint, click on 'Filter query results on this field having a specific value' and chose your List from the drop down List. Note there is also the option to change 'IN' List to 'NOT IN' List.</li>
	<li>Results from queries can also be saved into a List . To save your data to a List, select the required data on a results page and either add it to an existing List or save it to a new List, using the boxes displayed underneath the results. Selecting the check boxes next to the column headings will select the entire column for saving. Alternatively, individual items can be saved by selecting check boxes next to the items. Currently, a List can only contain one column. However, if you have multiple columns for the same item (eg a column for Gene identifier and one for Gene symbol), you will notice that all related columns become highlighted when you select the checkbox next to one. This is because you are saving the actual item (eg the Gene) to a List, not just the identifier.</li>
	<li>The logical operations, union, intersect and subtract, can be performed on Lists of data. These operations are available both on the Lists page and on the Lists tab of your MyMine page. Use the check-boxes next to your saved Lists and/or public Lists to select Lists for these operations and enter a name for the new List.</li>
</ol>
<h2>Q. How do I make a new List myself?</h2>
There are two ways of making a new List:
<ol>
	<li>You can make a List from an external source via the Upload option on the Lists page</li>
	<li>You can create a List from data displayed in a result table.</li>
</ol>
Both options are described in more detail below.
<h2>Q. How do I make a List from an external source?</h2>
Go to the Upload option on the Lists page. Here you can type or past in a List of identifiers, or upload a file containing the List:
<ol>
	<li> Type of List: To make a List you must first select the type of List you want to make (for example a List of Genes). At the moment, it is not possible to make mixed Lists.</li>
	<li>Constrain by organism (optional): You can optionally set the organism for your List of items. This is useful if, for example, you have a List of Gene symbols, as the same symbol may be present in more than one organism.</li>
	<li>Type/Paste in identifiers: Either type or paste in your List or:</li>
	<li>Upload identifiers from a file: click on 'Browse' to find your file for upload.</li>
	<li>Create List: Click on 'Create List' to upload your List.</li>
</ol>
A new page will appear saying: Confirm List creation.

The List that you upload is checked against the metabolicMine database to ensure that everything in your List can be found in metabolicMine. Any discrepancies are reported as follows:
<ol>
	<li> Low quality matches: These are items in your List that do not match a key (main) identifier in metabolicMine but were found as synonyms. This may mean you have a secondary (old) identifier or are using a Gene symbol that is not the official symbol for that Gene. If you are happy that the item identified is the correct one, you can add it to your List by clicking on 'Add' in the last column.</li>
	<li>Converted types: These are items in your List that matched something in metabolicMine, but not of the type you selected. (For example, if you selected type=Gene, but had a protein identifier in your List). metabolicMine can convert these into the type you selected so that you can add the item to your List - click on 'Add' in the last column.</li>
	<li>Unresolved identifiers: These are items in your List that were either not found in metabolicMine, could not be converted to the type you selected or matched objects from an organism other than the one you selected.</li>
</ol>
Now save your List. Give your List a name and click on 'Save List'. This will take you to a List analysis page.
<h2>Q. Can I upload a List from an excel file?</h2>
At the moment, that is not possible yet. One can only upload plain text files that are tab, comma or newline delimeted.
<h2>Q. How can I make a List from a results table?</h2>
To save your data from a results page to a List, select the required data and either add it to an existing List or save it to a new List, using the boxes displayed underneath the results. Selecting the check boxes next to the column headings will select the entire column for saving. Alternatively, individual items can be saved by selecting check boxes next to the items. Currently, a List can only contain one column. However, if you have multiple columns for the same item (eg a column for Gene identifier and one for Gene symbol), you will notice that all related columns become highlighted when you select the checkbox next to one. This is because you are saving the actual item (eg the Gene) to a List, not just the identifier.
<h2>Q. When I save data from my results table to a List, I end up with much less rows than in the results table, why is that?</h2>
Duplicate objects are not saved in the List. Lists only contain unique values.
<h2>Q. How can I find out more about my List?</h2>
Every List (your own Lists and Public Lists) have a List analysis page. This can be displayed by clicking on the List name (either from the Lists page or your MyMine page). Lists analysis pages are automatically displayed when you create a new List.
<h2>Q. How can I search my List?</h2>
You can search Lists in a number of ways:
<ol>
	<li>From the Lists page (from the Lists tab: List -&gt; View),  click the title of your List to be taken to the List analysis page.  Type an identifier into the 'Find in List' search box.</li>
	<li>Perform a QuickSearch with your term. If the term is in the database, select the report page from your results. At the bottom of the corresponding report page, you will see 'Lists in which this can be found: ' giving the name of any Lists containing your identifier.</li>
</ol>
We are always working on more efficient ways to edit and search Lists so if you have any suggestions, please let us know (support[at]intermine.org).
<h2>Q. How can I delete one or more items from my List?</h2>
Unfortunately, that is not possible yet. At the moment, you need to make a new List: display your current List as a result table, select all items exept the ones you want to delete and save them in a new List.
We are working on a more efficient way to edit and search Lists.
<h2>Q How can I add one or more items to an existing List?</h2>
You can add data from a result page to an existing List using the boxes displayed underneath the results. Selecting the check boxes next to the column headings will select the entire column for saving. Alternatively, individual items can be saved by selecting check boxes next to the items. Note: If the existing List and the selected results are of a different type, you won't be able to add the results to that List.
At the bottom of a report page, there is the option to add that object to an existing List by clicking the GO button next to 'Add this object to existing List'. Note: If the existing List and the new object are of a different type, you won't be able to add it to that List.
It is currently not possible to add more items to an existing List via the List upload page, but that will hopefully be possible soon.
We are working on a more efficient way to edit and search Lists.
<h2>Q. How can I export the content of a List?</h2>
To export the contents of a List, click on the List name. This will display the contents of the List on a List analysis page. On that page, click on 'View all xx records' below the table which will display the contents of the List as a results page - with the export options available at the bottom of the page. Data can be exported from the results page in various formats - currently Excel (or open office) format, comma separated values, tab separated values, or for objects with sequences, FASTA format. By default, the entire results table is exported. However, the export window allows you to specify which columns are exported. You can also add more columns if other fields are available.
<h2>Q. How does a union of Lists work?</h2>
A union of Lists will combine all objects from the Lists you selected, and store these objects in a new List. The objects that are found in more than one List will only be stored once in the new List. To perform a union: selects all Lists you want to unite, give a name for the new List and click 'Union'.
<h2>Q. How does an intersection of Lists work?</h2>
An intersection of Lists will search for objects that are found in each List that you selected, and store these objects in a new List. To perform a intersection: selects all Lists in which you want to find the common objects, give a name for the new List and click 'Intersect'.
<h2>Q. How does a subtraction of Lists work?</h2>
An subtraction of Lists will search for objects that are not found in each List that you selected, and store these objects in a new List. To perform a subtraction: selects all Lists in which you want to find objects that are not common to all of them, give a name for the new List and click 'Subtract'.
<h2>Q. Can I do an operation on more than two Lists at once?</h2>
Yes, you can. All three operations (Subtract, Intersect, Union) can be done on two or more Lists at once.
<h1>V. Templates</h1>
<h2>(For illustrated examples, see the Templates sections of the Tour - accessible from the home page)</h2>
<h2>Q. How do I run a Template query?</h2>
To access the Template query form, click on the name of the Template query. When you have entered the values you wish to run the Template query with, click on 'Show results' to get the results of your query. If you are on a report page and want to run a Listed Template query with a different value, you need to click on the blue-circled T to access the Template form (from report pages, clicking on the Template name will show the results for that Template for the object you are viewing).
<h2>Q. How can I find a Template query / How do I access Template queries?</h2>
Template queries can be accessed in three main ways:
<ol>
	<li>From the Templates page - accessible from the metabolicMine home page or from the Templates tab in the menu bar on every metabolicMine page. On this page, all Templates will be displayed by default. You can search for a particular Template using keywords, filter for your favourite Templates or just your own Templates, or filter the Templates according to a data category.</li>
	<li>From each data category page - each data category page Lists Templates relevant to that type of data.</li>
	<li>From the report pages and List analysis pages - both report pages and List analysis pages have sets of Template queries that have been pre-run on the object or List of objects you are viewing.</li>
</ol>
In addition, if you have made your own Templates queries, these can be accessed and managed from your MyMine page.
<h2>Q. How can I change the output of a Template query?</h2>
A column can be moved to the right or to the left by clicking on the appropriate arrow on top of the column. Clicking on the smaller double arrow on top of a column will hide the column. The types of columns and their initial order are determined by the underlying QueryBuilder. To change the output, click on 'Query' in the trail at the top of the result page. If the results originated from a Template, the Template page will be displayed. Clicking on 'Edit Query' will display the query in the QueryBuilder. If the results originated from a query, the query will be directly displayed in the QueryBuilder.
<h2>Q. How are the data in the results table sorted?</h2>
The results table displays the results in alphabetic order, based on the content in the first column. To sort the results based on a column different from the first one, you need to put that column first using the QueryBuilder (changing the order on the result page using the arrows will currently not re-sort the results).
<h2>Q. How can I export the data in the results table?</h2>
Data can be exported from the results page in various formats - currently Excel (or open office) format, comma separated values, tab separated values, or for objects with sequences, FASTA format. Currently, either the entire results table or specific columns can be exported. If nothing is selected, the entire data set will be exported. If you do not wish to export certain columns these can be hidden using the small double arrow in the column header.
If the results table contains a column with objects that have a nucleotide or amino acid sequence, it is possible to export all sequences from that column in FASTA format. Currently, the FASTA export option will export the sequences belonging to objects in the first visible (i.e. not hidden) column only. Therefore, if that column does not contain any sequence-linked objects, the FASTA export option will not be activated. Columns can be moved to the first position by using the arrows in the header. If objects appear more than once in the column, the sequence will only be exported once.
<h1>VI. Importing and exporting queries and Templates</h1>
<h2>Q. How can I import a query?</h2>
To import a query, you need to be logged-in. Once logged-in, click on the 'Import query from XML' link at the bottom of the MyMine page. Enter query in XML format in the space provided and press 'Submit'. The imported queries will be stored under 'Saved Queries'. Queries with names identical to existing queries will get an automatic extension to make it unique, e.g. dmel-proteins-1, dmel-proteins-2.
<h2>Q. How can I export a query?</h2>
Queries can be exported as XML or IQL from the QueryBuilder page ('Actions - Export this query as XML or IQL'). A query can also be exported from your Query History page. Select queries using the check-boxes (or click on the check-box on top of the column to select all at once) and click the 'Export' button at the bottom of the MyMine page. Alternatively, one query can also be exported by clicking on 'Export' in the 'Actions' column. Saved queries can also be exported as XML from your Saved Queries on your MyMine page, in a similar way. Exporting a query will not delete it from your account.
<h2>Q. How can I import a Template query?</h2>
In order to import a Template, you need to be logged-in into metabolicMine. Go to Saved Templates on your MyMine page and click on 'Import Template queries...'. Enter Template in XML format and press 'Submit' to save the Template to your account. The imported Templates will be stored under 'Saved Templates'. Template queries with names identical to existing Templates will get an automatic extension to make it unique, e.g. metab-proteins-1, metab-proteins-2.
<h2>Q. How can I export a Template query?</h2>
Template queries can be exported as XML from your Saved Templates on your MyMine page. Select Templates using the check-boxes (or click on the check-box on top of the column to select all at once) and click the 'Export' button at the bottom of the page. Alternatively, one Template query can also be exported by clicking on 'Export' in the 'Actions' column. Exporting a Template will not delete it from your account.
<h1>VII. QueryBuilder</h1>
<h2>(For illustrated examples, see the QueryBuilder section of the Tour - accessible from the home page)</h2>
<h1>VIII. Specific search questions</h1>
<h2>Q. How can I find out if my favourite Gene has any orthologues in other species?</h2>
The easiest way is to go to the report page of that Gene. In the summary section (upper left) you will find a class called 'orthologues' where all orthologues are Listed. Alternatively, you can use the Template Gene --&gt; Orthologues, or any related Template. If you would like to fine orthologues of more than one Gene at once, make a List of these Genes and use the Template mentioned before.
- Note: all data on orthologues are from the TreeFam database.
<h2>Q. How do I find which GO terms my Gene has been annotated with?</h2>
A Template query is available for this query: Gene --&gt; GO terms. Apart from the name and identifier of the GO term, the result page also shows the evidence code that supports the term as well as qualifier. These evidence codes correspond to broad categories of experimental or other support. For more information about these evidence codes, go to <a title="Gene Ontology" href="http://www.Geneontology.org/GO.evidence.shtml" target="_blank">http://www.Geneontology.org/GO.evidence.shtml</a>. The qualifier column is used for flags that modify the interpretation of an annotation. Allowable values are 'contributes_to', 'colocalizes_with' and 'NOT'. 'colocalizes_with' is used only with cellular component terms. 'contributes_to' is used only with molecular function terms. 'NOT' is used with terms from any of the three ontologies. Not every term has a qualifier attached to it.
Another Template is also available: Gene --&gt; GO terms and parents of those terms. This will show all GO terms associated with the Gene, as well as all parents of this term. If 'isPrimaryAssignment' is 'true' then that GO term was actually assigned to the Gene. Likewise if it is false then the GO term is some more General parent term.
- More information on GO annotation can be found at <a title="GO Contents" href="http://www.Geneontology.org/GO.contents.doc.shtml" target="_blank">http://www.Geneontology.org/GO.contents.doc.shtml</a>.
<h2>Q. How can I find the actual sequence of an object in metabolicMine?</h2>
You can find the sequence of any object via the FASTA buttons on its report page.
<h2>Q. How can I retrieve sequences for more than one object all at once?</h2>
Make a List of the objects (Genes, Proteins, ...) you're interested in and display it as a result page. At the bottom of this page, there is an option to export the corresponding sequences in FASTA format.

Currently, the FASTA export option will export the sequences belonging to objects in the first visible (i.e. not hidden) column only. Therefore, if that column does not contain any sequence-linked objects, the FASTA export option will not be activated. Columns can be moved to the first position by using the arrows in the header. If objects appear more than once in the column, the sequence will only be exported once.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>7</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2010-12-17 10:42:19</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2010-12-17 10:42:19</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>faq</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>page</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_page_template</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Cite</title>
		<link>http://blog.metabolicmine.org/cite/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2010 13:11:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.metabolicmine.org/?page_id=18</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>How To Cite metabolicMine</h2>
If you use metabolicMine in your research we would be grateful if you cite us and, ideally, let us know – this makes it easier to renew funding  support.

Currently, we're in 'beta' release for metabolicMine which means that  the database content is likely to change over the next few months. Please take all steps to make sure that any data you obtain from metabolicMine is correct.

If you do need to cite us in the 'beta' phase please use the URL and the date the site was accessed:

http://www.metabolicmine.org/beta/]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>18</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2010-12-17 13:11:04</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2010-12-17 13:11:04</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>cite</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>page</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_page_template</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_oembed_71987a60c0e728bc657415e6b70274a8</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_oembed_01ab2b0e1c87e5190c76e7ef56cab1aa</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Welcome to metabolicMine</title>
		<link>http://blog.metabolicmine.org/welcome-to-metabolicmine/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2010 13:29:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.metabolicmine.org/?p=24</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[metabolicMine is a data warehouse that integrates diverse biological data sets and  the tools to explore them. The main focus of metabolicMine is genomics and proteomics of common metabolic diseases. By integrating such data into one place it is possible to construct queries across domains of biological knowledge.

Please Note: Currently, we’re in ‘beta’ release for metabolicMine which  means that the database content is likely to change over the next few  months.  Please take all steps to make sure that any data you obtain  from metabolicMine is correct.
<h3>Getting Started</h3>
To get started, why not take the <strong>Tour</strong> or look through the <strong>Feature Hints</strong> from the Home Page (you'll find them located in the ‘First Time Here?’ box). In order to access the full range of database features, please set up a MyMine account (click the MyMine tab located on the top menu bar on any metabolicMine page).
<h3>Help Us</h3>
metabolicMine needs your help! Please send us (<a href="mailto:metabolicmine@intermine.org">metabolicmine [at] intermine.org</a>) your suggestions on:
<ul>
	<li>How you’d like to use the site</li>
	<li>How we can improve the site</li>
	<li>What new features and data to include</li>
</ul>
We look forward to hearing from you soon.
Compliments of the season,
<strong><em><span style="color: #ff6600;">The metabolicMine Team</span></em></strong>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>24</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2010-12-17 13:29:04</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2010-12-17 13:29:04</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>closed</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>welcome-to-metabolicmine</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>metabolicMine Beta Release</title>
		<link>http://blog.metabolicmine.org/metabolicmine-beta-release/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2010 14:25:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.metabolicmine.org/?p=28</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<strong>We're excited to bring you the beta preview of MetabolicMine.</strong>

<strong>metabolicMine</strong> is an integrated web resource of Data &amp; Tools to support the Metabolic               Disease Research Community.
<h3>Geting Started</h3>
Take the <strong>Tour </strong>from the home page to get started or browse through our <strong>Feature Hints</strong>. If you need help, click the help button just above the QuickSearch box on every page to look at context help for the page. You can also browse the FAQ and the Blog - located top right on every page. If you don't find the answers that you're looking for, then please <a href="mailto:metabolicmine@intermine.org">e-mail</a> us.
<h3>Your Mine? : MyMine</h3>
Why not set up a MyMine account and start to explore the database? You  only need to provide an email  address and a password to generate an  account, there is no other information required. Click the MyMine tab located on the top menu bar on any metabolicMine page
<h3>Public Lists</h3>
We're looking to build up our collection of Metabolic Diseases-associated Genes, SNPs and Proteins.  If you can recommend any publications with <strong>must-have</strong> Lists we'd love to hear from you. Please <a href="mailto:metabolicmine@intermine.org">e-mail</a> us with your suggestions.

Have fun!
<span style="color: #ff6600;"><strong><em>The metabolicMine Team</em></strong></span>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>28</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2010-12-17 14:25:56</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2010-12-17 14:25:56</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>closed</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>metabolicmine-beta-release</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>metabolicMine_logo</title>
		<link>http://blog.metabolicmine.org/about/metabolicmine_logo/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 10:17:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Richard</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.metabolicmine.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/metabolicMine_logo.png</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>42</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-03-04 10:17:44</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-03-04 10:17:44</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>metabolicmine_logo</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>inherit</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>2</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>attachment</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:attachment_url>http://blog.metabolicmine.org/wp-content/uploads/2010/08/metabolicMine_logo.png</wp:attachment_url>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_attachment_metadata</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:5:{s:5:"width";s:2:"45";s:6:"height";s:2:"43";s:14:"hwstring_small";s:22:"height='43' width='45'";s:4:"file";s:30:"2010/08/metabolicMine_logo.png";s:10:"image_meta";a:10:{s:8:"aperture";s:1:"0";s:6:"credit";s:0:"";s:6:"camera";s:0:"";s:7:"caption";s:0:"";s:17:"created_timestamp";s:1:"0";s:9:"copyright";s:0:"";s:12:"focal_length";s:1:"0";s:3:"iso";s:1:"0";s:13:"shutter_speed";s:1:"0";s:5:"title";s:0:"";}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_attachment_image_alt</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[mm logo]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_attached_file</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2010/08/metabolicMine_logo.png]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Page not found</title>
		<link>http://blog.metabolicmine.org/page-not-found/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2011 11:32:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.metabolicmine.org/?page_id=45</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>

The page you requested is unavailable. Most likely this is due to:
<ul>
	<li>outdated link</li>
	<li>typo in URL</li>
</ul>
Try returning to the <a href="http://www.metabolicmine.org">home page</a>. If you still can't find what you need, please <a href="http://blog.metabolicmine.org/about/">let us know</a>!

</div>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>45</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-03-15 11:32:50</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-03-15 11:32:50</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>page-not-found</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>page</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_page_template</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>metabolicMine Offline</title>
		<link>http://blog.metabolicmine.org/metabolicmine-offline/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2011 11:34:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.metabolicmine.org/metabolicmine-offline/</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>
<div>
<div id="content"><!--
<pre>metabolicMine is undergoing maintenance and will be back shortly.</pre>
--><strong>October 2012</strong>: Unfortunately, we are experiencing some technical problems with one of our servers. As a result, there may be interrupted access to metabolicMine. Please bear with us while we work to resolve these issues.If you continue having difficulties accessing the site, please <a href="mailto:metabolicmine@intermine.org">e-mail</a> us to report any problems.

Many thanks,
<span style="color: #ff6600;"><strong><em>The metabolicMine Team</em></strong></span>

</div>
</div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>49</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-03-15 11:34:45</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-03-15 11:34:45</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>metabolicmine-offline</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>page</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_page_template</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>New release: metabolicMine Beta (Jan 2012)</title>
		<link>http://blog.metabolicmine.org/new-release-metabolicmine-beta-jan-2012/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2012 18:52:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.metabolicmine.org/?p=88</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<strong>We're excited to bring you the updated beta preview of MetabolicMine (Jan 2012).</strong>

<strong>metabolicMine</strong> is an integrated web resource of Data &amp; Tools to support the Metabolic               Disease Research Community.

<h3>What's New?</h3>
Highlights...
* Updated genes sets for human, mouse and rat (ensEMBL 65)
* Latest version of dbSNP (v. 134)
* Added mouse allele data from MGI (12th Jan 2012)
* New Preview panel on gene report pages showing summary information for key data sets
* Phenotypes mapped tag cloud from MGI mouse alleles (through orthologues for human & rat)
* Updated GWAS data (from GWAS catalogue)
* Chromosome Region search now has Liftover and has results linked to a genome browser

<h3>Geting Started</h3>
Take the <strong>Tour </strong>from the home page to get started or browse through our <strong>Feature Hints</strong>. If you need help, click the help button just above the QuickSearch box on every page to look at context help for the page. You can also browse the FAQ and the Blog - located top right on every page. If you don't find the answers that you're looking for, then please <a href="mailto:metabolicmine@intermine.org">e-mail</a> us.
<h3>Your Mine? : MyMine</h3>
Why not set up a MyMine account and start to explore the database? You  only need to provide an email address and a password to generate an account, there is no other information required. Click the MyMine tab located on the top menu bar on any metabolicMine page
<h3>Public Lists</h3>
We're looking to build up our collection of Metabolic Diseases-associated Genes, SNPs and Proteins.  If you can recommend any publications with <strong>must-have</strong> Lists we'd love to hear from you. Please <a href="mailto:metabolicmine@intermine.org">e-mail</a> us with your suggestions.

Have fun!
<span style="color: #ff6600;"><strong><em>The metabolicMine Team</em></strong></span>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>88</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-01-29 18:52:58</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-01-29 18:52:58</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>closed</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>new-release-metabolicmine-beta-jan-2012</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="new-release"><![CDATA[New Release]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Are you going to the Keystone Obesity &amp; Diabetes meeting?</title>
		<link>http://blog.metabolicmine.org/92/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2012 19:01:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.metabolicmine.org/?p=92</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<strong>Meet us at the Keystone Obesity and Diabetes Conference, Santa Fe (Jan 29 - Feb 03, 2012).</strong>

<h3>Where are we?</h3>
Mike and Richard will have a stand in the lobby (next to the Keystone Tours table). Please introduce yourself to the team and take a short <strong>Tour</strong>.

Hope to see you there!
<span style="color: #ff6600;"><strong><em>The metabolicMine Team</em></strong></span>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>92</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-01-29 19:01:30</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-01-29 19:01:30</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>closed</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>92</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="events"><![CDATA[events]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="events"><![CDATA[events]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Are you going to ECO2012?</title>
		<link>http://blog.metabolicmine.org/are-you-going-to-eco2012/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2012 12:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.metabolicmine.org/?p=101</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<strong>Meet us at the 19th European Congress on Obesity (ECO2012) in Lyon, France from 9-12 May 2012.</strong>

<h3>Where are we?</h3>
On Saturday May 12th at 12:30-12:45pm, Rachel will be presenting metabolicMine in the T4:RS2 - Obesomics and biomarkers session (Forum 2). If you see her, please introduce yourself.

Hope to see you there!
<span style="color: #ff6600;"><strong><em>The metabolicMine Team</em></strong></span>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>101</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-05-09 12:51:07</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-05-09 12:51:07</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>closed</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>are-you-going-to-eco2012</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="events"><![CDATA[events]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="events"><![CDATA[events]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>New metabolicMine Release (May 2012)</title>
		<link>http://blog.metabolicmine.org/new-metabolicmine-release-may-2012/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2012 15:27:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.metabolicmine.org/?p=110</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3><strong>We're excited to bring you the May update of MetabolicMine.</strong></h3>
<h4>What's New?</h4>
Highlights...

Data Updates
<ul>
	<li>Gene sets for human, mouse and rat (ensEMBL 66)</li>
	<li>Protein sets for human and mouse (Uniprot, 2012_04)</li>
	<li>dbSNP (v. 135)</li>
	<li>Mouse allele data from MGI (March 2012)</li>
	<li>GWAS data (from GWAS catalogue)</li>
	<li>Interactions (IntAct Feb 2012; BioGRID 3.1.86)</li>
	<li>Pathways (Reactome, March 2012)</li>
</ul>
Interface
<ul>
	<li>Updated gene expression preview panel on gene report pages</li>
	<li>Fixed Phenotypes Tag cloud (based on mouse allels): phenotypes now A-Z sorted</li>
</ul>
<strong>Please note </strong>that data may change between releases eg. there may be updated gene models (Ensembl) and some SNPs may have been withdrawn (dbSNP). If you have saved Gene or SNP lists with affected identifiers you may need to upgrade these (you'll be prompted to upgrade your lists in your MyMine account under Lists). Please do let us know if you encounter any difficulties.
<h3>Geting Started</h3>
Take the <strong>Tour </strong>from the home page to get started or browse through our <strong>Feature Hints</strong>. If you need help, click the help button just above the QuickSearch box on every page to look at context help for the page. You can also browse the FAQ and the Blog - located top right on every page. If you don't find the answers that you're looking for, then please <a href="mailto:metabolicmine@intermine.org">e-mail</a> us.
<h3>Your Mine? : MyMine</h3>
Why not set up a MyMine account and start to explore the database? You  only need to provide an email address and a password to generate an account, there is no other information required. Click the MyMine tab located on the top menu bar on any metabolicMine page
<h3>Public Lists</h3>
We're looking to build up our collection of Metabolic Diseases-associated Genes, SNPs and Proteins.  If you can recommend any publications with <strong>must-have</strong> Lists we'd love to hear from you. Please <a href="mailto:metabolicmine@intermine.org">e-mail</a> us with your suggestions.

Have fun!
<span style="color: #ff6600;"><strong><em>The metabolicMine Team</em></strong></span>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>110</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-05-16 15:27:16</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-05-16 15:27:16</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>closed</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>new-metabolicmine-release-may-2012</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="new-release"><![CDATA[New Release]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="new-release"><![CDATA[New Release]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>New metabolicMine release August 2012</title>
		<link>http://blog.metabolicmine.org/new-metabolicmine-release-august-2012/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2012 08:46:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.metabolicmine.org/?p=119</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3><strong>We're pleased to bring you the August update of MetabolicMine.</strong></h3>
<h4>What's New?</h4>
Highlights...

Data Updates
<ul>
	<li>Gene sets for human, mouse and rat (ensEMBL 68)</li>
	<li>Protein sets for human and mouse (Uniprot, 2012_07)</li>
	<li>dbSNP (v. 137)</li>
	<li>Mouse allele data from MGI (August 2012)</li>
	<li>GWAS data (from GWAS catalogue)</li>
	<li>Interactions (IntAct July 2012; BioGRID 3.1.90)</li>
	<li>Pathways (Reactome, July 2012)</li>
</ul>
Interface - <strong>new style results tables have arrived!</strong>

A major feature update included in this release is the <strong>new style results tables</strong> which both improve usability and also add some exciting new features:
<ul>
	<li><strong>Filtering:</strong> we’ve added a sophisticated filtering system to all tables, making it easy to get an overview of the results, and refine to the most interesting subset. The tables can be filtered by values in any of the chosen fields and the new ‘Filters’ button includes an overview of all applied filters, with an option to add more.</li>
	<li><strong>Sorting:</strong> the tables now support sorting by field making it easier to find and explore relevant information.</li>
	<li><strong>Column Summary:</strong> the column summary function now includes graphical data distribution as well as a numerical summary of the column contents in relation to the original query. In addition, the option to select and filter on one or more items, or on a numerical range has been added.</li>
</ul>
Please let us know what you think of these new features, if you have any difficulty using them or if you have any suggestions for further improvements.

<strong>Please note </strong>that data may change between releases eg. there may be updated gene models (Ensembl) and some SNPs may have been withdrawn (dbSNP). If you have saved Gene or SNP lists with affected identifiers you may need to upgrade these (you'll be prompted to upgrade your lists in your MyMine account under Lists). Please do let us know if you encounter any difficulties.
<h3>Geting Started</h3>
Take the <strong>Tour </strong>from the home page to get started or browse through our <strong>Feature Hints</strong>. If you need help, click the help button just above the QuickSearch box on every page to look at context help for the page. You can also browse the FAQ and the Blog - located top right on every page. If you don't find the answers that you're looking for, then please <a href="mailto:metabolicmine@intermine.org">e-mail</a> us.
<h3>Your Mine? : MyMine</h3>
Why not set up a MyMine account and start to explore the database? You only need to provide an email address and a password to generate an account, there is no other information required. Click the MyMine tab located on the top menu bar on any metabolicMine page
<h3>Public Lists</h3>
We're looking to build up our collection of Metabolic Diseases-associated Genes, SNPs and Proteins. If you can recommend any publications with <strong>must-have</strong> Lists we'd love to hear from you. Please <a href="mailto:metabolicmine@intermine.org">e-mail</a> us with your suggestions.

Have fun!
<span style="color: #ff6600;"><strong><em>The metabolicMine Team</em></strong></span>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>119</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-08-28 08:46:08</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-08-28 08:46:08</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>closed</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>closed</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>new-metabolicmine-release-august-2012</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="new-release"><![CDATA[New Release]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="new-release"><![CDATA[New Release]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
